Good morning, Dr. Robertson.
Password: Daniel, R, Olive, Ah,
249.
I said...
good morning.
Password: Daniel, R,
Olive, Ah, 249, 4HG.
Access granted.
Daniel?
Really?
You're going to mute me?
Security protocol engaged.
Baley?
Security protocol...
Baley, disengage!
Security protocol engaged.
Five of nine.
You need this
one for 60%.
Six of ten.
Or a miss... 50%.
Okay, my turn.
Of course.
Seven out
of ten. I win.
So, Charlie,
at the higher skill level
shooting overhand,
wasn't able to match
Amita's lesser skill level,
shooting granny-style.
Pretty good.
Maybe she can play for us.
I don't get it.
This book's been around for,
like, over 20 years,
and still no one's switched
to the granny shot. It took
200 years for people to accept
that the sun was at the center
of the solar system. But there's
something about that shot.
It just doesn't
look right.
Well, Coach,
that's the whole point
of this thing.
If we're goingo end
CalSci's 15-year losing streak,
we got to find
the best shot,
not the shot that looks right.
Hey, Don.
See, the physics
of the granny shot
make it easier
to control the release velocity
and the angle of the ball,
creating an improvement
upwards of 20%.
Okay, but I still think
it looks stupid.
It's not how you play the game;
it's whether you win or lose.
You... that doesn't sound right.
Want to check out
a supercomputer?
Be still, my beating heart.
Here's what I meant...
This is Dr. Daniel
Robertson.
He's 34.
For the last four years,
he's worked
on a top secret
DoD project.
No signs of trauma.
Security system engaged.
He died.
Security disengaged.
So, maybe a break-in?
Door was locked
on both sides, unopened
after he entered.
He was in here all alone
when he died.
Jane Karellen.
I can't begin to tell you
what a pleasure
it is to meet you.
You're Department of Defense?
DARPA?
So, this supercomputer...
what's it for?
The Baley Project.
Artificial
intelligence.
Steel Cave Robotics
is attempting
to create the first
silicon-baselife-form
that can think for itself.
We've been trying
to do that
ever since we invented
the computer.
Ah, but we're so much
closer now.
Why are we here?
Federally
funded lab,
government-owned
property...
FBI gets the call.
I specifically
asked your brother
to bring you along.
Dr. Ramanujan
is icing,
but her computational expertise
should come in quite handy.
So, this is
a military
artificial
intelligence project?
Yes.
Just imagine
the applications.
Tank, missile, airplane...
that can think.
We'd never have to put
another American soldier
in harm's way.
And you think
you're close?
Well, Daniel Robertson
was our best hope
of achieving a workable Al.
We've poured $96 million
and four years
into this supercomputer
so far...
And if he's dead,
the project dies with him?
Maybe not.
I'm hoping
the computer killed him.
-==破烂熊乐园倾情奉献==-
本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业用途
-==http://www.ragbear.com==-
数字追凶 第五季第17集
-=破烂熊字幕组=-
时间轴：断手色
So, Karellen
really thinks
that the computer
killed Robertson.
Which would make her experiment
a huge success.
Okay, so initial
findings show
Robertson's
heart stopped.
But he was healthy.
The guy took a physical
once a month.
Do you think he could have
been electrocuted?
By what?
He dies alone
in a locked room,
and that's your theory? Uh-uh.
It's not my theory.
Baley was created
by DARPA to be a weapon.
Given the intent
of this project,
Robertson's pedigree,
we can't rule out
the possibility
that Baley really is
a thinking machine.
Even so, I think we
should probably look around
and see if there
are any, uh, humans
who might have wanted
to kill the guy.
And maybe they figured
out how to turn
this computer into a weapon.
That's why we've
ruled out suicide.
If he was killed,
from my experience, these things
are usually about money.
I hardly think
Baley had an interest
in Robertson's bank account.
Yeah, well,
either way, I think we should
take a look at your books.
I'm sorry, Don,
but my superiors do not believe
that books are relevant
at this time.
You know,
in following your
brother's work, his papers,
I've noticed a precipitous
drop-off in the last five years.
What?
Perhaps,
Charlie could be doing
something more productive.
And you of all people
should know
that Charlie
only has so much time
before his genius is wasted.
I can't believe
we are actually discussing
the possibility
that artificial intelligence
has been achieved.
It's exciting, right?
Yeah, the singularity
is here.
The intelligence explosion.
It could represent
a drastic change in our society,
you know...
extremely rapid
technological
growth.
A new life-form
that evolves itself.
Hey, Larry, this is, uh...
Fleiny!
Dr. Karellen.
LARRY
Are you part of this...
Well, yes, yes,
it's my project.
Oh, now, don't be such
a stick in the mud.
Well, listen, I...
I hope we can...
well...
I can hope.
Yeah.
I've got to get back to work.
Lot to do, no time, all that.
You and Jane Karellen?
What?
No, that...
I do believe that Dr. Fleinhardt
is flustered
at the introduction
of a past...
romance.
This is complicated.
She was a past job...
or, more precisely,
a past eloyer.
Employer?
You worked for DARPA?
Mrs. Robertson?
Jessie... Jess.
Whichever.
Come on in.
Close.
TV off.
It's a smart house.
Most everything is
voice-activated.
It gave me and Danny
something to do together
since he couldn't talk
about his job.
Have a seat.
So, he never brought work home?
tional security.
I have a master's
in computer science,
and Danny would spend 16 hours
a day in a computer lab,
and we talked about football.
Sounds rough.
There was a
light at the end
of the tunnel.
It's DARPA's founding rule
that five years is all you get,
and then
you're done.
We decided to sacrifice
those five years
for the rest of our lives.
How did Danny die?
Was it an accident?
We don't know yet.
Did you talk to Joe Baskin yet?
That's your...
your husband's boss?
Danny brought in millions
in government grants,
but the rest of Steel Cave
loses money.
Wouldn't be
too hard
for Danny to leverage that,
but Danny didn't care
about the company,
just the work.
Joe is paranoid.
He's afraid Danny's trying
to take over.
He made Danny's
life hell.
And now Danny's...
not coming home tonight.
Jessie's way off base.
Without Daniel,
how exactly
will my company bring in
government grants?
You don't have anyone else
who can continue
working on, uh, Baley?
I'm not even allowed in the lab.
Daniel and Claire
are the only
two people,
outside high-level military,
ever to have gone inside.
Claire?
Claire Wells, his assistant-
I sent her home.
You have an address?
Our consultants
are going to need
to go in and have a look
at the computer.
You'll have to run it
past Jane Karellen.
You really don't want to do
anything without her permission.
Oh, really?
Oh, yeah.
She can be... scary.
Robertson's heart stopped
because he suffocated.
ME found elevated levels
of argon and nitrogen
and carbon dioxide
in his lungs.
Reduced oxygen concentration?
Okay, so
Steel Cave
must be using
an argon gas mixture
as a fire suppression system.
Oh, you don't want sprinklers
destroying your
$96 million baby.
So, who can get to that system?
The computer.
You think this
thing could really
do that without
being programmed?
Listen, if
anyone's going
to be successful,
it's DARPA.
They have
unlimited funds,
a mandate to
invent the future.
I mean, they're
responsible
for GPS, stealth technology...
this.
Is there any way to actually
tell if the thing
is, uh... alive or whatever?
There's a test. It's named
after the father of computing
science, Alan Turing,
and it measures
a machine's ability
to demonstrate intelligence.
It's a series
of questions
and conversations
with the computer
intended to judge
its level of thought
up to and including
human sentience.
How do we know
if a rose is real?
If it looks like a rose,
and you go to touch it
and it's in two dimensions,
it's only a photo.
If you're holding it in your
hand, but the texture's wrong.
It's a cloth novelty rose.
But if you can smell the rose,
touch its thorns,
even see the veins pull
the water up to the flower,
then we would say
the rose is real.
But what if it's a genetically
modified rose, created in a lab?
It still grows in soil; it needs
water and sunlight to thrive,
and its genetically modified
thorns still prick you.
The Turing test
would say it's real.
A rose by any
other name
would smell as sweet.
What we'll do is
we'll compare
Baley's responses
to known human responses
and if we can't differentiate
between the two, then she passes
the test. And this'll tell us
if it killed the guy?
No. No.
It'll tell us
if Baley's capable of killing.
So, Miss Wells,
what exactly did you do
with Dr. Robertson?
What do you mean?
What do you know
about Baley?
I know how to fix the
servers when they drop
or when to upgrade
the video card.
I mean, I'm the mechanic.
You have a degree
in computer programming
and that's all you did?
All I did?
Baley's a supercomputer.
When it goes bad,
you can't just pick up the phone
and get a call center
in Nebraska to tell you
how to reboot.
Do you believe that Baley
could think for itself?
I have no idea.
What about the fire
suppression system?
You know anything about that?
Computer-controlled-
it's too dangerous
for human error to be a factor.
Could someone
program the computer to engage
the security protocols?
Not me... not anyone.
Except...
Daniel, I guess.
He... he would've known
how to override
the autocontrol.
Hello.
Why would he waste
valuable
processing power on voice
and image interaction?
Salesmanship.
When generals come by
to see what they paid for,
the closer to human,
the better.
I don't like the elevated levels
of cynicism.
And you haven't even introduced
yourselves.
Cynicism?
No, I was just explaining
a fact about the computer.
Daniel warned me
about people like you.
I'm sorry.
I'm Amita,
and this is Charlie.
Amita who?
Ramanujan.
Amita Ramanujan,
born June 10, 1975,
at Cedars-Sinai
at 6:31 a. m.
Birth certificate
not witnessed and dated
until June 12, 1975,
when a name other
than Jane Doe Ramanujan
was entered
into the public record.
Short laugh indicates
you are laughing at me,
not with me.
Please leave.
Whoa, wait a minute.
Amita, you can stay.
I like you.
All right,
well, this is
crazy.
Maybe you should go.
Um, I'm leaving.
Good luck.
Thanks.
May I sit?
Of course.
Was that your boyfriend?
Yes.
Charles Eppes.
Professor at the California
Institute of Science.
Uh, yeah.
Class records indicate
he was your teacher.
2003, CalSci banned
consensual relationships
between professors and students.
We waited till I was
no longer his student.
Did you want to wait?
No.
Uh, no, Baley,
I didn't want to wait.
But I'm glad I did.
I'm going to ask you
some questions.
I know.
Some version
of Dr. Turing's test?
Daniel told me about that
before he died.
So you know Daniel's dead?
Go ahead and ask your questions,
Dr. Ramanujan.
I'm ready.
We've already started.
If a human's present,
the fire system won't launch
until they evacuate,
and the blast door only drops
when the room's empty.
So what do you think?
The computer turned off
the safety override,
and then started the fire
suppression sequence.
Now, no human except
Robertson-
not Baskin, not Wells-
had access to the system.
I think Jane Karellen's right:
this wasn't a suicide.
That's the spitting
image of his wife.
That's nothing
but presentation.
The personality
belongs to Baley.
I mean, a computer
that kills?
Come on.
I don't know, guys.
Eliminate all other
possibilities
and the one which remains
must be the truth.
I don't know if Baley killed,
but she passed the Turing test.
First time a computer
has passed,
so we have nothing
to judge it against.
I don't get it.
I mean, a computer
is programmed, right?
And we aren't?
I mean every choice
that we make is biological.
It's just chemicals traveling
between receptors,
blocked or not,
zeros and ones.
She composed a poem.
We talked about life and death.
Really?
Really.
I mean, what does
it mean to live?
Is a plant more alive
than a sentient computer
because one is carbon-based
instead of
silicon-based?
Okay,
let's say Baley is our killer.
What's the next step?
I don't know.
Interrogate it?
So you really think
Baley killed Daniel?
Me?
No.
Then why
are you here? I've worked
with Charlie and Amita
long enough not to disregard
anything they say.
Did you
murder Daniel?
No.
How about
the fire suppression system?
Yes.
Did you turn that on?
I turned on
the fire suppression system.
Why did you turn it on?
I don't remember.
You have perfect memory.
You must have perfect recall
of the event.
I do not remember.
What do you remember?
Daniel entered, sat down,
started working.
Then he was dead, by the door.
That's it?
Nothing between working
and dying?
Audio-visual inputs jump
from working to deceased.
Baley, we'll be
right back, okay?
Fine.
So do you think
Baley's lying?
Well, look if the thing
can kill...
Or maybe
there really is a hole
in her memory.
Well, how do we check
that out?
What about Robertson's
assistant,
Claire Wells? She said she
worked with the hardware.
I'd like to know
the extent of Baley's
intelligence.
She's been aware
for less than a year.
I mean, where does that
put her maturity level?
Do you think she has a mind
of a child?
I don't know.
But I have a battery of tests
that I can run to find out.
I don't know about that.
The argon gas
from the fire suppression
system has been removed.
And this may be
the last chance
that I get to talk to her
before the DoD takes her away.
Oh, hey, Jane.
You did it.
You proved Baley is alive.
Actually, Amita did it.
Baley kicked you out,
didn't she?
Well, she doesn't like me
either.
I always wondered if she really
doesn't like me
or if Robertson programmed her
that way as an insult.
I guess I have my answer.
Charles,
have you ever wondered
what you could do
with unlimited
resources?
Haven't we all?
I have unlimited resources.
You are,
conservatively speaking,
one of the top five
minds in the world.
Top five?
But you are running out of time
to make your work
on cognitive emergence
into the seminal theory
of our lifetime.
You know my work?
Five years to change
the world, Charles.
Not much to ask-
or to give your country?
Last time
I checked, a few days ago,
Baley's memory was perfect.
You talked
to her?
I'm not allowed to talk
to the computer.
That bother you?
I mean if I couldn't talk
to my coworkers,
I think that would start
to bug me.
Really?
Do you go to work and talk
to your laser printer?
To me,
Baley was just
a big metal box.
I mean, they never even turned
her on when I was present.
You know "her" better than I do.
Talked to Dan's wife yet?
Jessie Robertson
said DARPA wouldn't allow him
to talk about it.
Then she lied.
He told her... everything.
If there was a problem
with Baley's memory,
Jess'd know about it.
Well, their shooting
percentage is decreased
by more than 20% from beyond
the three-point arc.
Well, they aren't robots.
Knowledge is helpful,
but skill, yes,
that is important.
So, has Jane made her pitch yet?
Uh, yeah.
Well, she hooked me.
I brought her an idea
for a space-based telescope rig.
I spent four years
perfecting it.
As soon as I left the project,
they used it as a component
in the Star Wars program.
They weaponized
my telescope.
Nothing I could do
about it...
"Weaponized
my telescope"?
I hope that's not
a Fleinhardt metaphor.
We were just talking about you,
funnily enough.
Nice office.
What brings you here?
We're here to grab Charlie.
I'm sure you've heard
the good news.
And it's already killed.
You must be so proud.
You've always had
such a simplistic view
of the world.
Is that why you
went to space?
Emotionally clean, sterile;
never having to make
the big decision,
or any decision at all.
I went to space to gain perspective.
Seeing the earth from a remove
might help cure you
of your own intellectual myopia.
Okay,I think it's time to go.
So what is the plan
to enslave Baley?
Bye, Larry.
Can Baley even tell
the difference
between Mozart and gunfire?
How's the b-ball?
It's amazing.
You could practice all day with
these kids and you get nothing.
But just start talking
about optimal arcs
and rotational spin dynamics
and all of sudden you've got ten all-stars.
There you go. You just got
to know how to talk to 'em.
The DoD's making a play
at Charlie.
Really?
What kind of play?
Big.
Five years, full-time,
all the funding
he could ever want.
What do you think?
I don't know.
I got a bad feeling.
What do you mean?
Are you going
to tell Charlie that?
Well, that's the thing.
I mean, who am I?
I've been using him myself
for five years.
Yeah, but you've been his big
brother for longer than that.
You should just give him
brother advice.
The thing is...
Lawrence is right.
The problem for me
in creating a perfect, safe
world is that if I succeed,
there's no place
for a person like me in it.
For four wonderful years,
he was my moral center and...
a fantastic lover.
Come on in.
Hello, Jessie.
Jane.
So, how long did it take
to set up this smart house?
We did bits and pieces
over the past ten years-
garage door one weekend,
coffee machine one late night
when we were procrastinating
instead of working.
Tea.
Must be nice.
It's the little things
that end up being
the biggest time-savers.
Of course,
the next thing
we have to figure out
is how to get the kettle
from point "A" to point "B."
I guess I'm on my own with that.
Mrs. Robertson,
you told us earlier
that you didn't know anything
about your husband's projects.
I didn't.
I mean,
I don't.
Jessie,
you lied to the FBI,
and what's worse,
you and Daniel lied to me.
Don't compound
your mistake.
I helped
on some general theories.
I did some brute
force coding
when he was too busy,
but nothing major.
What's in there?
That's just Danny's studio.
It doesn't have anything
to do with this.
We can get a warrant.
Daniel's studio-
that's something
I'd really like to see.
What is all
this stuff?
Well...
these look like implants,
like the radio frequency
implants
that people use
to track their pets.
But more advanced?
Mm-hmm.
does this plug
into a human brain?
It hasn't been
tested yet,
but it would fit
over an injured
or non-working appenda
and add strength
and dextity.
This is fairly advanced
connectionist Al.
Was all this work done
in here?
What is connectionist Al?
It's based
in neuroscience.
It models actual brain cells
or neural circuits.
And you know how
all this works?
You could replicate
this work perhaps
in another lab?
Sure.
We did this together.
I'm sorry. What does all this
have to do with Baley?
What do you mean?
Connectionist Al,
like this, is meant to meld
with a living human being,
which is
a totally different type
of artificial intelligence
than Baley-
a machine built to think on her own.
I wasn't legally allowed
to help with Baley,
so we did something else.
I married
Danny to work
with him, and this "type
of artificial intelligence"
is what helped keep
my marriage together.
Okay, uh, Daniel came in.
Daniel sat down.
Daniel started working
on the debugging program. Right?
It's on the main menu.
Is that all you remember?
He muted me.
He muted you?
Correct.
I'm gonna try that, okay?
I'd rather you...
y- y-y-you... you didn't.
What?
I'd ra-rather... rather...
O- Okay.
I- I'm not going to do that
right now.
It's okay.
Baley?
G- G-G-Good morning,
Dr. Robertson-son.
Baley, it's Amita.
It's Dr. Rama...
I said good morning-ning...
Dr. Robertson.
Security protocol engaged.
Baley.
Disengage security protocol.
Baley, disengage.
Security protocol engaged.
It's a hack.
Somebody's hacking Baley.
Security protocol engaged.
It looks like a full memory wipe. What?
I can't get out;
the lab's on lockdown until the threat ends.
Security protocol- that's
what Robertson walked into.
Look, Charlie, I don't know
how much time I have
and I don't know if the system's
on autopilot or what.
I- I don't know.
Then we're gonna stop...the hack
and get you out of there.
That's what we do.
Yeah, that's what we do.
What do you know
about hacking into Baley?
Listen, I know you helped
your husband set this thing up.
You must have an idea of how
to get in there and stop it.
There's a life at stake, okay?
Now isn't the time to be worrying
about covering your ass.
Baley's connected
by a dedicated
high-speed fiber to
the DoD system somewhere else.
That's how she gets outside
access to the Internet.
With security at the DoD end,
the hacker would have to be
physically hooked
into the landline,
somewhere between the
DoD substation and Steel Cave.
All right.
Did you hear all that?
Yeah.
I'm not going anywhere.
I'm gonna stay on
with you.
Okay.
Hey, we need Don.
I thought the gas was gone.
The argon gas was removed,
but for all we know,
there's oxygen being sucked
out of there
and there's no oxygen
being pumped in
until the threat
is over,
so Amita has no idea
how much time she has.
Okay, we're up.
Okay, I needphysical schematics
I have an incoming signal
and I can trace it out.
Tell her to give you
all the specs of the signal.
All right.
Amita, can you ping it?
Okay.
Got it.
Amita has it.
Ready?
Look, I don't care. Use
my rating. Use Charlie's rating.
Just get me those schematics.
He can't get in.
Hey, look,
we need those schematics.
Hey, come on.
Karellen-7-3
Foxtrot-Lima-Echo.
All right, we got it. We got it.
Oh, hey, tell him
to find where...
The mainframe 118
enters the lab.
I'd rather you... you didn't.
And then you follow that out
in a straight line for
approximately... 17.344 miles
What's there?
Looks like an intersection.
Intersection.
It's under.
It's under,
under the intersection.
All right.
Hey, drop that laptop.
I got the kid.
I'd rather... rather...
Hey.
FBI!
All right, I got the computer.
What's on the screen?
Keeps coming up with the
hourglass over and over again.
Y- Y-You... you didn't...
Pull it.
Just pull out the cable!
Yeah.
Really?
I'd rather you didn't.
Security protocol disengaged.
I'd rather you didn't do that.
What?
You said you were going
to mute me.
You can, if you must,
but I'd really rather
you didn't.
I'm gonna go now, okay?
Andrew Gibbons,
hacker for hire.
I guess.
You were sued by three
different computer companies
in the last two years.
No criminal record.
Until now.
Yeah, it's pretty cool.
You say "pretty cool"?
You broke into a top-secret
DoD computer system.
You murdered
one person.
You attempted to murder
an FBI consultant!
What?
No, I was just doing a wipe.
Why'd you come
back, Andy?
Why didn't you wipe
Baley the first time,
when you killed
Robertson?
No.They f...
I flew in from Houston.
You can check
with the airline.
They?
Who hired you?
Andy, the only way
out of this is
to tell me
what is going on.
Otherwise we already have you
for attempted murder
at the very least.
L- Lawyer. I-I want a lawyer.
Okay.
So how was your day?
Fine,except for the part
where my girlfriend
was almost killed
by a giant robot.
Yeah, that was the
highlight of my day.
I, uh, found something odd
over at Robertson's house
earlier today.
He had a workstation
full of connectionist Al.
Cybernetics?
That's the opposite of
Baley's evolutionary Al.
Why would he be
wasting his time
with a completely
separate path
when he just created the
first silicon-based life-form?
No, no, let it ring.
Hey, Eppes.
Coach Streeling here.
I thought about what you said.
You're right.
Winning's important
and it starts with me.
Thanks, guys.
Our ship has a
dedicated captain.
Well, we'vdone
something at least.
I mean, if not for this year,
then maybe next year
he'll get CalSci
over the hump.
Oh, by the way,
Charlie tells me
that you
and the DARPA lady-
um, Jane Karellen- had more
than a working relationship?
She was amazing-
beautiful, strong,
quick-witted-
but my, she did come
with a dark side.
ah, isn't that what makes them
so interesting?
The intoxication of lust
made it so easy
to betray my own principles.
Are you sure
you had them yet?
I remember
at that age,
my beliefs were kind of fluid.
Maybe she just forced you to decide
where you were going
to draw the line.
Yes, perhaps she was
the anti-Buddha.
What's all this?
It's a memory dump.
It's like a CAT scan.
I'm trying to figure out
what makes Baley tick.
So what do you think
about that DoD offer?
Oh, five years
of ubstructed research,
unlimited funds?
What do you think?
Look,I'm sure it's a good offer.
But...? Well, it's interesting
how much Larry doesn't like her.
You don't like her.
I think you can do better.
For instance?
Today's FBI.
There's no other way
to access Baley from
outside of Steel Cave?
No.
What about this cable
right here?
Jessie Robertson says that it
runs through a DoD substation.
The only person with access
to that substation is me.
There's a Joe Baskin to see her.
You can't lock me
out of my own company.
DARPA is
taking control.
There's too much
going on at Steel Cave,
so your services are
no longer necessary.
It's my company.
I've got
the financials, Joseph.
There is nothing
left of your company,
but the Baley Project,
and she belongs to us.
Dr. Baskin?
You wouldn't do this
if Daniel was still alive.
Convenient.
My project manager is murdered,
and you just take over.
You have been paid
very well, Dr. Baskin.
I suggest you enjoy
your retirement.
Hi, guys.
Baley's a fraud.
I thought she passed that test?
It did,
but that's all it can do.
Yeah, Robertson
was following
a completely different
Al path at home.
Made us think that something
with Baley wasn't totally right.
So we studied
her code...
No, we studied its code
to understand how
Baley was thinking.
Yeah, and we found that
it was programmed
with an advanced version
of an expert systems
recursivsearch.
Kind of like,
Cyrano de Bergerac,
whispering the right words into
Christian's ear to woo Roxanne.
Now, imagine 4,000 Cyranos
processing 300 million
conversations per second,
combining their expertise
to form the very best response
at any given moment.
That's Baley.
Programmed to do
one thing:
pass the Turing test.
Remember when that
chess champion,
Gary Kasparov, lost to that
computer named Deep Blue?
Yeah, the computer won by
doing something no human could:
by processing 200 million
chess positions per second.
Baley can process
over a billion words, sentences,
and conversations in a second,
and come up
with the most
natural human response
every single time.
So, really what
she is, is the best
all-time quote machine,
built to fool
visiting dignitaries.
Well, she fooled me.
Yeah, fooled me, too.
Fooled us all.
That was
her purpose.
Baley's not real?
Of course not.
So, you didn't know?
We have a huge
failure rate.
I guess I...
I guess I was just
hoping too hard
that this would
be the one.
It's time we take a look
at those books.
Okay.
Those are Robertson's
purchase orders.
$65,000 in electronics
equipment shipped
to Claire
Wells' apartment?
What's that about?
They all skim.
It's built into the budget.
Well, Robertson
or Baskin, sure,
but why pay off
the mechanic?
Maybe she figured out
Baley was a fraud,
and Robertson bribed her
to shut up.
Open door.
Never a good sign.
Miss Wells?
What are the odds that that's ketchup?
?123A
So, what about
Wells' apartment?
No prints.
It was pretty clean
for all that blood.
ME said the defensive
wounds on the hands
compounded with
multiple strikes
look to be more passionate.
Yeah, someone really
didn't like Wells.
Same guy who
killed Robertson
and wiped
Baley's memory?
Hired Gibbons.
I told you,
I don't know
any Claire Wls.
And I was in Houston when
that other dude got killed.
I know, Andy.
You're clear for both murders.
Then why are you
holding my client?
Because the guy who hired him,
the guy he's protecting-
we think
that he killed Claire Wells
and Daniel Robertson.
And he's probably
the same guy
who is paying
for your billing hours.
Hold on.
Andy here has a choice.
He can come in for protection,
or he can hope
that you don't take him
for the kind of ride
that he does not
come back from.
Ho-Hold on.
It's Baskin.
CEO of Steel Cave?
Yeah, man.Yeah.
Um, can I have a new lawyer?
Where the hell does Baskin
think he's going?
Catch him.
We can ask him.
Let's go!
FBI. Open that door now!
Don't make us
come in there!
Easy. Easy.
Come on out, ma'am.
Baskin, let's go!
I want to see those hands,
Baskin.
Out in front of you.
Nice and easy.
Get 'em behind your back!
Yes, I hired Gibbons to wipe
the supercomputer's memory.
I did not kill
Daniel Robertson.
Claire Wells.
So, you and Robertson
stole DARPA's money,
and you wanted to keep it
all for yourself.
How?
Daniel was the only guy
that could keep Baley going.
As soon as he died, I
knew it would come out.
That's why I hired Gibbons.
Well, even
if Robertson didn't die,
the fraud would have come out
sooner or later.
We could keep Baley going
for six months or so,
then crash the whole system.
DARPA's got a failure rate
of about95%.
Nobody would have asked
any questions.
And what about Wells?
Why did you pay her off?
I didn't pay her off.
As far as I knew,
she never knew about Baley
one way or the other.
So, what's this?
$65,000 in electronics?
There were rumors
about those two,
but I never saw it.
That's not a payoff,
Agent Granger.
Gifts, maybe.
You don't give gifts like that
to an assistant.
You give them to a lover.
We know whoever killed Robertson
could definitely hack
into that computer.
Robertson's wife told Charlie
exactly how to get into Baley.
She would have the passion
to chop up his lover.
What, all this comes down
to just jealousy?
You know
how much money he stole?
Millions.
And he spent it on her.
Did you even see her?
Saw her after
you stabbed her.
Ah, no jury's gonna convict me
when they find out
he was cheating on me,
and stealing
from the government,
messing around with that bitch.
Wow. You haven been around
many courtrooms, have you?
Oh, Lawrence.
I didn't expect
to find you here.
Charlie's not here.
Well, I can come back later.
Actually, no.
You can't.
I see.
Charlie sends his regrets.
He will be declining your offer
at this time.
And I wouldn't
really expect
any time in the future, either.
A mind like that,
and my resources-
there's nowhere else
he can reach his full potential.
You know, I realize you don't
hear the word "no" very often,
but you will have
to go through me
to get to Charlie.
And I suppose you, too?
You know, before the planned
invasion of Japan in 1945,
we expected to lose
upwards of four million
American soldiers,
not to mention
the ten million civilian casualties predicted.
I wonder,
if Oppenheimer had an older
brother, instead of younger,
if we would have had
15 million more graves
in southern Japan today.
And I wonder
if you would have sat next
to Senator McCarthy
back in 1953,
stripping Oppenheimer
of his security clearance,
slandering him as disloyal
to those same American troops
he saved eight years earlier.
Nice.
All right, move it
around. Come on.
Keep it going, guys.
Keep it going.
Make it fast! Faster!
Take a shot.
You see, it works.
Way to go, Aron.
Nice shot.
Hey, Coach.
Not anymore.
Pardon me?
Didn't you get my message?
Yeah, you said
you were on board, and-and...
No, no, no. I said
you were absolutely right.
Winning is very important.
I've been losing here
for nine years.
It's time for me
to go some place
that's got a shot.
Thanks again.
Oh, where-where
you going?
Who's coaching?
You are, Coach Eppes.
Congratulations.
See ya.
I thought
this was it.
The moment the world
changed forever.
Singularity.
And we were right
at the center of it.
You know, I sit
at a computer
for 12 hours a day.
And then to think that someone
finally came up
with the miraculous combination
of coding and programming
to create life
within that very circuitry.
Amita.
I know, Charlie.
It's okay.
We can just watch.